So, let's have a little refresher on how we move lines by changing the parameters.
So, if we have a line of equation y equals w_1x plus w_2,
where w_1 and w_2 are constants,
it looks like this, w_1 is the slope and
w_2 is the y-intercept which is where the line intersects the y-axis.
Now, what happens if we increase w_1?
Well, we increase the slope so that means the line rotates like this.
If we decrease w_1,
then we're decreasing the slope so the line rotates like this.
Now, what happens if we increase the y-intercept w_2?
Then the line moves in a parallel way up like this.
And if we decrease w_2,
then the line moves like that to the bottom.
That's really all we're going to need for the tricks that are coming.