So, here's our first trick that we will align
closer to a point that we're going to use in a linear regression.
It's called the absolute trick and it works like this,
we start with a point,
and a line, and the idea is that the point wants the line to come closer to it.
So, let's put some numbers here,
the point has coordinates p comma q,
where p is a horizontal coordinate and q is the vertical coordinate.
The line has equation y equals w_1x plus w_2.
In here w_1 is the slope and w_2 is the y-intercept.
So, an easy way to move the line closer to the point
pq is to just add one to the y-intercept,
and then there is, the line moves up.
Now let's add something to the slope two to
make the line rotating the direction of the point.
This is going to look a little strange but it's going to make sense very soon.
So, this distance over here is p because it's
the horizontal distance from the y-axis to the point.
So let's just add that, let's add p to the slope,
and now our new slope is w_1 plus p,
and that rotates the line in this direction.
Now our new equation is y equals w_1 plus p times x plus w_2 plus one,
and that's pretty much what the absolute trick is about.
Notice some subtleties though,
notice that we moved the line a little too much,
and we actually went over the point and kept going,
we don't want this, in general in
machine learning we never want to take big steps like this.
Instead what we want to do is take tiny steps.
So, in order to take a tiny step we'll just do
the exact same thing we did except we multiply everything by a small number.
So let's take a small number called the learning rate, let's say alpha,
and instead of adding one to the y-intercept and p to the slope,
we will add alpha times one to the y-intercept,
and alpha times p to the slope.
Now the line moves up by a little bit and rotates a little bit,
so we don't have that risk of going too far.
Our new equation is going to be w_1 plus p times alpha times x plus w_2 plus alpha.
So our new slope is w_1 plus p times alpha and our new y-intercept is w_2 plus alpha.
So we're doing better but there's still a little subtlety.
What happens if the point is not on top of the line but underneath the line?
Well, same thing except now instead of adding we just subtract to get
our new equation w_1 minus b times alpha times x plus w_2 minus alpha.
The reason is if we subtract alpha to the y-intercept the line moves down instead of up
and if we subtract p times alpha to the slope the line rotates in this direction instead.
Something more interesting is this,
and that will explain the reason p is there.
If the point is not on the right of the y-axis but on the left of it,
than we still add one to the y-intercept because we need the line to move up,
but the fact that now we're adding p to the slope and p is now
a negative number means that our line now rotates in this direction,
so that's a reason for p to be there.
Another reason for p to be there is this, check this out.
If this distance is small then p is small,
so we're adding a small number to the slope.
Now, if the distance is large then p is
large so we're adding a large number to the slope.
It makes sense that if the point is really
close to the y-axis we want to increase the slope by a little bit.
Whereas if it's far want to move it by a lot more.
So, let's do an example to make this more clear.
Let's say we have the point 5 comma 15 and the line y equals 2_x plus three,
so this means the distance from the point to the y-axis is five,
now let's say our learning rate is 0.1.
So, we're adding 0.1 times one to
the y-intercept and that moves the line up by a little bit.
Also we are taking five multiplying it by 0.1
and adding that to the slope which makes the line move in this direction,
this means our new equation is y equals 2.5 x plus 3.1.
Now, check out what happens if the point is in the left,
we're still adding 0.1 to the y-intercept to move the line up,
but now to the slope we're going to add the product of
0.1 and minus five, that's minus 0.5.
This means our new equation is going to be 1.5 x plus 3.1.
As you can see the slope moved in
a different direction which made it go closer to the point.
So that's it, that's the absolute trick,
and we're going to use it extensively in linear regression.