In this project you will apply
supervised learning techniques and
an analytical mind on data collected for the US census,
to help a fictitious charity organization called
Charity ML identify people most likely to donate to their course.
You will first explore the census data and learn how it is recorded.
Next, you will apply a series of transformations and
preprocessing techniques to manipulate the data into a workable format.
You will then evaluate several supervised learners of
your choice on the data and consider which is best suited for the solution.
Afterwards, you will optimize them all you've
selected and present it as your solution to charity ML.
Finally, you will explore the chosen model and its predictions under the hood,
to see how well it is performing when considering the data its been giving.
I look forward to seeing your work.