So, with Kaggle, you can actually set up your own competitions?
Yes. Absolutely.
We're going to set up a competition for students to be able to
share their work through Kaggle and just get them onto the Kaggle platform.
How can they go about doing that?
How easy is that process?
How easy is it to get integrated into the community?
Yeah. I'm going to, answer it backwards.
So, getting integrated into the community, pretty straightforward.
People are fairly welcoming.
You can just write your Kernel,
make it public, and post on the forums,
you know, can I get some feedback? What do you guys think?
Here's my approach to this problem, what would you do?
And people tend to be pretty responsive and interested,
because it's a large community and people are really excited about data science.
Do you know how large the community is?
We definitely have over a million registered users.
Okay.
Yeah.
That great. I mean that's a huge community.
Yeah. No, it is. And it feels vibrant.
Yeah.
We also have something called In-class.
Which is a way that you can set up your own competitions.
So, you would pick a data set,
and then you split it
into testing and training just like you would. So, no one would see.
So, testing and training for people to see,
and then a third validation set that nobody would see. So, it would be hidden.
And then you would give people access to it and they would train their models,
and then upload their answer file for the, you know, the-
What they think should happen. Yeah. Right.
Yeah exactly. Then you'd validate it against the specific,
the secret, validation data set
and then ranking based on whatever sort of metric you're using.
So, if you were just looking at,
you probably wouldn't use like raw percent correct.
You could if you wanted to, right.
If it was sort of a problem that made sense there.
But I've seen people use these for obviously,
In-class, hence the name.
But also, if you just like, when you do a hackathon or just a project for some friends,
or like a little friendly competition.
Yeah, cool.