As an optional portion to this project,
you can test your skills in our ML Charity Competition on Kaggle.
In this screen cast,
I'll show you how to get started with making your predictions on the Kaggle platform.
First, you will need to sign in or create an account.
Don't worry, it's free.
Once you've logged in, you can see an overview of
basically how this project is run on this first page here.
You should already be pretty familiar with
the dataset as it's the same one that you used in the project.
If we look at the data portion,
you'll see that there are three files here to assist you in completing this competition.
The census.csv file is the exact same one you used throughout the project.
There are two additional files,
this test_census.csv looks a lot like the census CSV file,
but it has the response value removed from the dataset.
That's something that you'll want to predict and
then be able to submit into the competition.
The example submission file shows you exactly the way that
your results should be submitted into the Kaggle competition.
There are two ways that you can work with these datasets.
The first way is you can download them and just work with them from your local machine.
The second way is that you can do things through
kernels on the Kaggle competition platform.
By doing things in kernels,
you allow the community as well as your peers to understand how
you solve the problems and to learn from what you put together in your notebook.
When you work with the Kaggle kernel,
you'll notice that you have access to
the files that were available in the data portion earlier.
So, notice that this is exactly like what you used before and then if we have
the test data and then you'll notice that
the test data is going to be what you're
going to want to predict this income column with.
So down here, they don't have the income column because that's what you're going to
predict and then essentially what you want your final results to look like,
is you want this unnamed index column along with what you'd predict for
that column and you'll only submit that in for your submissions for the competition.
If you go back to the leader board,
you'll notice that if you strictly submit the example submission,
you'll end up with a score of 0.5.
Hopefully, by building a machine learning model,
you can actually beat that metric.
Once you feel like you are confident with your result,
there's a submit predictions button and you can simply upload your submission file.
Remember, it will need to be in the same format as this example submissions file.
So, if you download this.
So, you'll want your submission file to look like this,
where it has an Id column which is basically just the row
Id and then whether they're an income bracket one or income bracket zero.
So, you can see that in the test submission,
they just predict everything to be a one but
you'll want to have some of those be ones and some of
them be zeros based on the row and what you think that row should be.
If we look at the directions down here,
you'll notice that it says,
"Zero values indicate the individuals make less than 50 K and
one are for the values in the test set that make more than 50 K." You don't
want to basically change that file so that some are ones and some are
zeros and you'll predict those ones and zeros based on some machine learning model.
Good luck and I hope you enjoy the competition.