Correct logarithm is the answer since it satisfies that beautiful identity that says,
the logarithm of a product is the sum of the logarithms.
Thus, our product numbers becomes a sum of the logarithms of the numbers.
In this case, we get minus 3.245.
Now in this class, we'll be using log as a logarithm base two,
and the reason is information theory.
So here's our summary. We have our three configuration of red and blue balls.
Now we have the probability of the ball being red and blue,
and the product of them according to the sequence,
which is the probability of winning the game.
In the next column, we'll take the logarithm base two.
But since the numbers are less than one,
the logarithm is negative.
Thus, if we take the negative of the whole equation,
we're now dealing with positive numbers.
And in the last column, we'll just divide by four
because what we'll use as definition of entropy is the average of
the negatives of the logarithms of the probabilities
of picking the balls in a way that we win the game.
Thus, for the first bucket,
we get 0 entropy,
for the second one we get 0.81,
and for the third one we get one.
This is going to be our formula for entropy.
In the slightly more general case of
five red balls and three blue balls, we get the following.
The negative of the sum of
five times the logarithm of the probability of picking a red ball,
which is five over eight,
and three times the logarithm of the probability of picking a blue ball,
which is three over eight.
We can see that this is a large number since this set has a lot of entropy.
In the more general case with m red balls and n blue balls, this is the formula.
As the probability of picking a red ball is m divided by m plus n,
and for a blue ball it's n divided by n plus
n. And this is the general formula for entropy when the balls can be of two colors.