Well, let's see. A woman who works at an office.
In the table, there's two women who work and both downloaded WhatsApp.
So, let's say, it's safe to assume that
recommending WhatsApp to this new person is the best idea.
Now, for the man who works at a factory,
we'll see that there's another man in the table who works and he downloaded Snapchat.
So, we'll proceed to recommend Snapchat to the new person.
And finally, the girl that is in high school.
Well, we see that in the table,
there are three students and they all downloaded Pokemon Go.
So, we'll go ahead and recommend Pokemon Go to this new person.
But now, that's how a human thinks.
For the computer, it's harder to repeat this procedure.
However, the computer can ask
a slightly more technical question like this one: between gender and occupation,
which one seems more decisive for predicting what app will the users download?
This question sounds slightly ambiguous, but if you think about it,
the answer does make sense. Let's give it a try.