In order to cook up a formula for entropy,
we'll consider the following game.
In this game, we'll start with a configuration of balls;
say red, red, red,
and blue, and we'll put them inside the bucket.
Now, what we do is we pick four balls out of this bucket with
repetition and we try to get the initial configuration;
red, red, red, blue and if we do, we win.
Let's say we pick our first ball and it's red.
We record the color and put it back.
Then, we pick a second ball and it's red.
So, we again record the color and put it back.
Then, we pick a third ball,
say red and record the color and put it back.
Notice that we pick the same ball again.
This is completely okay. Finally, we pick a fourth ball.
Now, we got blue, we record it, and put it back.
We recorded red, red, red,
blue. So, we win a lot of money.
If say we got the colors red,
blue, blue, red, then we will win no money at all.
That's the game. Now, the quiz question is,
which one of the three buckets is the best to play the game
with and which one is the worst? Enter your answer below.