So here's something very interesting about perceptrons and it's that
some logical operators can be represented as perceptrons.
Here, for example, we have the AND operator and how does that work?
The AND operator takes two inputs and it returns an output.
The inputs can be true or false but the output is
only true if both of the inputs are true.
So for instance, if the inputs are true and true then the output is true.
If the inputs are true and false then the output is false.
If the inputs are false and true then the output is false.
And finally, if the inputs are false and false then the output is false.
Now, how do we turn this into a perceptron?
Well, the first step is to turn this table of true/false into a table of zeros and
ones where the one corresponds to true and the zero corresponds to false.
And now we draw this perceptron over here which works just as before.
It has a line defined by weights and a bias and it has a positive area
which is colored blue and a negative area which is colored red.
And what this perceptron is going to do is it will
plot each point and if the point falls in
the positive area then it returns a
one and if it falls in the negative area then it returns a zero.
So let's try it. The one one gets plotted in
the positive area so the perceptron returns a one.
The one zero gets plotted in the negative area so the perceptron returns a zero.
The zero one gets plotted in the negative area so the perceptron returns a zero.
And finally, the zero zero also gets plotted
in the negative area so the perceptron returns a zero.
Other logical operators can also be turned into perceptrons.
For example, here is the OR operator which
returns true if any of its two inputs are true.
That gets turned to this table which gets turned into this perceptron which is very
similar as the one before except the line has different weights and a different bias.
What are the weights and bias for the AND and the OR perceptron?
You'll have the chance to play with them in the quiz below.