Welcome to this course on unsupervised learning. I'm Josh.
And I'm Jay.
Were both really excited to be working with you through this course.
Unsupervised learning is one of the three main branches of machine learning.
In contrast to supervised learning,
where you have a label or a value that you're trying to predict,
in unsupervised learning, you are interested in
grouping data together that don't have labels.
In this course, you will learn some common techniques that are used for
unsupervised learning as well as how to implement them using scikit-learn.
Jay and I both really enjoy teaching others about technology,
machine learning, and programming.
So we're very excited to be joining you in this course.
Let's get started.