This is a great resource for showing how the k-means algorithm works.
Let's take a look at a couple of examples and see what might
happen with different sets of data and different numbers of clusters.
To begin, let's go ahead and choose a set of data.
Maybe we choose something like this Gaussian mixture.
Imagine we put a centroid here.
What this algorithm is telling us is basically all of
the points belong to this algorithm at the beginning,
and maybe we have another point here and a third point Here.
Then we could run the algorithm.
If we say "Go",
you can see that the first thing that happens is
each centroid is assigned to a certain number of points,
and then if we update the centroids,
they move to the center of that grouping.
If we reassign the points,
you can see in this case, none of them updated,
the centroids didn't move and what happens is the algorithm's
done at that point because the centroid stayed static for two iterations.
Now, if we restart and we choose the Gaussian mixture again,
but let's say we have two points that are down here and maybe one that's
up here and so we think there's three clusters and we run the algorithm like this.
The first thing that happens is all of our centroids are
assigned and then we update them and then we
reassign the points and then we update
the centroids and you can see again we end up with the same clusters.
This should give you some intuition behind how the k-means algorithm actually
works behind the scenes where it's finding the points that are closest to the centroid,
updating the centroid, looking at the points that are closest in its new position,
updating the centroid and doing that until the centroid no longer moves.
But let's see what might happen if something goes wrong.
Let's do the Gaussian mixture model again.
We have two centroids that look like this,
and we perform the clustering algorithm until it's done and it ends up like this.
But then if we restart and we have that exact same set of data,
and maybe we put one here,
we add a centroid down here and we add a centroid up here,
now running the algorithm shows that we get a different grouping.
It's not the case that the groupings will always end up the
same and which grouping is actually the best.
This is something that we'll explore in the next concepts.