From what you now
know about how the k-means algorithm works we should chat about a couple of things.
There are two areas of concern that still need to be considered.
First, you might be thinking,
" Do the random starting points of the algorithm matter?"
And the answer to that is yes.
Second, can we be sure that the ending results of
the clusters will be the same no matter where the starting points are?
And the answer to that is no.
Unfortunately, depending on the random starting points,
there might be different ending results for the clusters.
Since we're not guaranteed that any set of starting
values will end up with the same grouping of the data,
a common way to make sure we actually find the best clustering of the data,
is to run the k-means algorithm many times each with different starting points.
Actually, scikit-learn does this for you.
The random starting points should be substantially different from one another.
We don't want to have starting points that are almost the exact same in each attempt.
If we still end up with the same groupings for each run of K-means,
that's great, because we can feel confident about that grouping.
Alternatively, if we have groupings that differ when we change
the starting points we want to make sure that we choose the best grouping.
The best grouping for a set number of clusters k,
is defined as the grouping or the average distance
from the points to the centroids, is the smallest