You've already seen in supervised learning,
that it's imperative for you to scale your variables.
K-means is another algorithm that uses
distances to determine which group a point belongs to.
So feature scaling is absolutely necessary for this algorithm.
There are number of scalings you might choose to do.
From standardizing, or Z-score scaling to normalizing, or min-max scaling.
We usually use standardizing with clustering
algorithms as well as with transformations like PCA and ICA,
which you'll see later on in this course.
Alternatively, we use normalizing when scaling the coloring of an image.
If you do not scale your features,
the features with much larger variance will dominate the importance in clustering.
Even if it's just because of the choice of units,
you do not want this to happen.