Consider this dataset.
On the x-axis is the amount of time in minutes it
takes to run five kilometers for 100 individuals.
On the y-axis is each individual score on a standardized test on a scale from 200 to 800.
Notice that this provides two clusters,
one exists up here at the top for those with higher test scores,
and another exists here for those with lower test scores.
However, let's say we change the x-axis to represent seconds instead,
and the y-axis to represent test scores.
Then we have two different clusters,
one for those with faster running times,
and another set for those with slower running times.
When using minutes, the computed distance between
individuals is smaller than when using seconds.
Similarly, we have larger distances between individuals when
using lower test scores rather than standardized test scores.
This is just one example of how
feature scaling might change the final clusters determined by a model.
For this reason, it's important to standardize your data before clustering.