It turns out that with any distance-based machine learning model,
you're going to want to scale your data.
If the features that you have are on completely different scales,
you're k-means algorithm could come up with completely different clusters.
In this notebook, we will look at
the most common ways that people use to scale their data.
First, let's read in the necessary libraries and create our dataset,
which is going to be stored in DF.
The first thing that they want us to do is just take a look at the data.
So, let's look at a header.
It looks like there's just two columns,
one for height and one for weight.
We could also take a quick look at
describe or plot them against one another if we wanted to.
These are two of the most common things that I do.
Also, looking at the shape, it's sometimes useful.
So, it looks like we have 200 rows,
two columns, no missing values.
There's two types of scaling methods that are extremely popular.
One is called the MinMaxScaler and the other is called the StandardScaler.
The MinMaxScaler scales everything between zero and one,
where the StandardScaler scales everything to have a mean of zero and a variance of one.
Let's take a look at both of these and practice.
So here, you can see that, basically,
we're doing in instantiate a fit and a transform on our data all in one step.
We're storing that in this df_ss,
to stand for data frame with a standard scalar, feature scaling.
Then, what's happening here is we're just turning that back into a Data Frame,
adding on the columns,
and then doing a quick scatter plot of the dataset. So, it looks like this.
If we wanted to, we could actually do this with the original data set,
and so you can see it looks like this,
it looks pretty much the same here and
now they want us to do the same thing using the MinMaxScaler.
So, to get some practice ourselves,
let's go ahead and we're going to basically do the same process,
but we're doing it with the MinMaxScaler.
So, instead of the StandardScaler,
let's use MinMaxScaler and then we'll do a fit transform.
I'll call this MM and then similar to up here,
we just want to turn that into a data frame.
Change the column names and plot the data.
So, this to be the columns and then plot them against one another.
Oh, I didn't run the cell.
So here, you can see when we use the StandardScaler,
they're both centered on zero and they're basically between the range of
three and negative three and negative two and two on this axis,
but a little bit to go, a little bit beyond that,
and then when we look at this dataset,
you can see that it's between zero and one for each variable.
So, the MinMaxScaler scales things between zero and one,
where the StandardScaler has mean zero standard deviation of one or variance of one.
So, you can see that this is what it looks like if we were to create
10 different clusters in this height weight dataset.
In this last part, they just want us to do this with the scale datasets.
So, this one was using just the regular one,
but we could do the same thing using the scale dataset.
So, one of them is called SS and the last one is MM,
and in this particular case,
it doesn't look like the scaling matters.
So, in our response,
we could write about how in this case the scaling didn't matter so much,
but in other instances,
it could be the case that the scaling would completely change these clusters.