Take a look at these points here.
You can see that even without labels,
there are ways that we might group these points together.
In this particular plot,
it appears that there are two groups.
Now, look at this set of points here.
Here, it appears that the points in this plot can be grouped into three groups.
If we were to add a new point say here,
we could easily say that it is similar to the rest of these points.
Similarly, if we were to add a point say here,
we could see that it belongs to this group.
Grouping data together in this way is known as clustering.
This is the first type of unsupervised machine learning that we'll look at.
Take a look at these points here,
notice how they follow a pattern.
Another type of unsupervised learning,
we can use patterns in our points to reduce the dimensionality.
So in this case,
we could reduce from two dimensions to one.
This is a second type of unsupervised learning called dimensionality reduction.
Throughout this course, you will get some practice with
each of these two types of unsupervised learning.