One of the most popular clustering algorithms in
all of machine learning is known as the K-means algorithm.
This algorithm is used to cluster books,
and articles that are similar which has helped to identify otherwise anonymous authors.
It's also used to cluster similar movies and music
for the purpose of recommending new items on Netflix or Spotify.
Another very common use case of K-means is to
cluster the behaviors of customers to better understand,
similar groups of purchasers,
and identify the best approach for recommending
new items based on their purchasing habits.
Using K-means to group similar customers,
is done by advertising platforms from Google,
to Facebook, to Amazon.
Maybe someday, it will even be a part of the education space where we're
develop learning strategies based on clustering different types of learners.
With that, let's take a closer look at how K-means works and put it to use on a data set.