To see how the k-means algorithm works, consider this dataset.
On the x-axis, is the distance I travel on any given day,
and on the y-axis is how awesome the place I went was.
This cluster of points that are all the same distance are when I go to work.
Some days, I get to build awesome content,
which is fun, so these points represent those days.
Other days, I see students struggling with content and that bums me out,
so those days aren't as much fun.
My parents live pretty far away,
which is represented by this distance.
I really like getting to see them,
so this cluster here represents the times when I get to see them.
You can see that overall,
being at my parents is pretty awesome,
but it doesn't happen very often.
The clustering of these groups is what k-means does when it looks at data.
In the k-means algorithm,
we group the points closest to one another together into k groups.
Here, k might be two clusters.
One, to represent traveling to work and a second to represent visiting family.