The K in K-means relates to how many clusters you want to split your data into.
So in a case like this,
three clusters looks like it probably works best.
Alternatively, if we had this set of points,
three clusters doesn't seem right.
In this case, two clusters looks like it makes more sense.
When we have lots of data in a large number of dimensions,
how do we decide how many centers to choose?
Choosing K in practice is often a mix of art and science.
Sometimes, researchers are interested in choosing
a specific K value based on preconceived ideas about a topic.
One example of this happens right here at Eudacity,
we believe that students generally fall into one of three categories;
students who are new to a field,
students who are interested in scaling up their careers,
or students who are changing careers.
So, it makes sense to use K-means with K equal to three to see if our data
supports this idea of three types of students or three clusters of students.
Sometimes, we don't have an idea of
how many clusters there should be before we collect data.
For these cases, we'll look at another method
that can be used to find the number of clusters in a dataset