You've now had some practice
with identifying the number of clusters in the data
set when you can clearly see clusterings of point,
as well as when there are some preconceived ideas about how many clusters might exist.
But what about when you have no idea how many clusters might be in the data?
How might we determine the k in k-means for these cases?
For this I would like to introduce a method known as the Elbow Method.
The way this works is that for any set of data,
we could try fitting k-means with differing numbers of k,
then for each value of k we can measure
the the average distance of each point from the center point of the cluster.
If we kept track of the average distance for each value of k,
we could create a plot that looks like this.
On the x-axis, you can see that we have the number of clusters or k. On
the y-axis we have the average distance of
each point from the center of the cluster across all of the clusters.
You can see here as the number of clusters increases,
the average distance from each point to the center decreases.
However, with each additional center,
the impact on the average distance is not the same.
With small values of k,
each additional center greatly decreases the average distance.
With larger values of k this makes less and less of an impact.
The main point of interest in this plot is what is known as the Elbow.
At this point, we have found a number of clusters that
significantly reduces the distance from each point to the center of the cluster.
At the same time increasing k does not appear to have a substantial impact.
Finding the Elbow can be a bit of a judgement call.
You're looking for the point when increasing k no
longer leads to a large decrease in the distance from the centers.
Let's get some practice with this.