So, if you go onto the next page,
you'll notice that there's a notebook available called Changing
K. What I like to do when I'm in the classroom,
is actually open this up into a new tab.
If you move it into a new tab,
you'll see that it opens that up behind the scenes.
But the notebook that we were on,
is this Changing K notebook.
In this notebook, what we're going to take a look at,
is fitting the k means algorithm to a set of data points.
In this case, the first thing we should do,
is import our necessary libraries.
Then, once we have our libraries read in,
let's take a look at the first question.
The first question says,
we want to simulate data and we're going to use this helpers to file to do it.
So, the first thing they want us to do,
is actually read the documentation.
So, that we understand how to use this function.
So, if we just run that cell,
you'll notice that it tells us,
basically, there's the simulate data function.
It'll simulate N points with the features as whatever
this is listed as and the number of centroids that were used to create the data.
As this part here.
So, this is a really useful function,
to be able to just quickly simulate the data we want.
In this particular example,
we want 200 points,
five features and four centers.
So, let's go ahead and create that dataset.
So, 200 points, five features and four centers,
this should be h. Cool.
So, looks like we're good to continue.
Don't forget that h, because you're reading it in from that helper file.
So, because we fit this model with four centers,
it asks, "What should the value of K be?"
The value of K should be four.
If we run that cell, it tells us, "Yeah, that's right".
Then, the next thing we want to do,
is actually run the KMeans algorithm on our dataset,
to see what it looks like if we have four centroids.
So, this gives us a little glimpse at what that process should look like.
First, we should instantiate our model,
then, we fit it to the data.
Then, we predict the labels for our data and then,
this last step down here that you can see,
is where we plot the data.
So, here, we need to instantiate, then,
we fit, we predict and then,
we'll get a plot for our data.
This is the basic process that you should follow with
any of the unsupervised algorithms that you'll see.
The first thing that we might do,
is actually look at the documentation.
You can see that I read it in here,
but a quick Google search should bring you to the KMeans documentation.
So, you can see we're importing from the sklearn.cluster library,
we're importing this module.
Essentially, KMeans will take the number of clusters and a whole bunch of other things,
which we don't really have to mess around with.
The main thing that we should see is,
that we want to take KMeans with four centroids.
So, if we go back here and we fit the KMeans algorithm,
by passing four here and then,
the next thing we should do is fit the model.
If you look at the documentation,
you can also find all the methods that are available on this.
So, you can see they have KMeans.
Here's where they use a predict,
they would get different labels,
there's a fit predict, there's a fit.
So, there's a bunch of things in the documentation.
I'm just going to show you how this works quick.
Once, you've done this a couple of times,
it becomes pretty natural.
So, we want to fit to our dataset.
Then, what we want to do,
is predict the labels.
Again, you could do this all in one step,
if you want it to, using that fit predict.
This is called kmeans_4 and this I
should actually use the model that I created, so model_4.
Right. So, I fit that model,
I store it here and then,
I use that model to predict our data.
So, I instantiate, I fit that model on the data.
Then, I take that model and I use it to predict on the dataset.
So, this is the usual process.
Instantiate, use that instantiate model to fit to your data and then,
use the model that you create there to predict on your dataset.
So, here you can see each of the colors as what our models predicted,
what cluster those points belong to.
In the next page,
you'll do this on your own.
You'll see what it looks like, if you create it without
four but with different numbers of clusters.