So in the previous screen cast for clustering,
you saw how we could simulate our dataset and then fit
our data with the kmeans model and see how many cluster show up.
Then when it was your turn,
you tried this with different numbers of clusters.
So, you might have created a model with two clusters instead of four,
fit that to your dataset and finally predicted
on your dataset to see what your data would look like.
You can see this is what it would group into if there were two clusters.
Then again, you could try it with seven.
This process will hopefully become repetitive in a way that helps you
see how it can be extended to
other algorithms as well because it's the same process you go through for all of them.
Then, this is what it would look like if we had seven.
So, you can see how the colors are associated with the different clusters in this plot.
Then finally, once you fit kmeans,
there's a score method which takes the data.
The score is an indication of how far the points are from the centroids.
So, here they want you to do it for 1-10,
and keep track of the number of centroids.
So, this one takes a little bit,
but 1-11 will give us one through 10.
So, four each centroid and range 1-11,
because this is not inclusive and this is.
We want to obtain a score for each model and basically we can follow
this same step procedure and we want to fit it with a certain number of centers.
You don't actually want the labels,
what they want us to do is run the score method.
I'm just going to get rid of these.
So, we fit the kmeans model and then we score it on the data.
I'm going to create a vector of scores.
So, I'm just going to call this scores,
it'll just be a list and I'll do
scores.append and I'll just append the model scores into this and I'll do it as a tuple,
where I keep track of the center and the score.
So, this should take the center and the model score,
put it into a tuple and then attach it into that list.
Then it says, "Try creating your own scree plot."
I'm just going to create centers,
equals, list, range 1-11.
Then I have those two lists and I can just do a simple
plt.plot and then whatever's on the x axis,
which is in our case,
the centers and then whatever's on the y-axis which should be the scores.
I think that should do it. Then we want plt,
we could put a title on this and call it scree plot and
plt.x label which is the number of centers and then plt.y label,
it's the score or the average distance from centroid.
Let's see if this breaks, oh, and it did.
That's like an R syntax thing, it's a comma.
It should actually be like the absolute value.
Python does some weird stuff where, yeah, there we go.
So, Python does some weird things where they want all the scores,
as they get lower to be worse.
So in this case,
if we take the absolute value,
which was a strange thing.
But this absolute value is the actual distance,
where before it was like the negative of that and that's
just because of the way that scikit-learn does scores.
So based on this,
you can see that down here is actually the elbow that's where it flattens out.
So, up until four there's substantial drops and
the average distance and then it flattens out pretty substantially.
If we look at this,
cool, and you can see that they look pretty close to the same.
Using this scree plot how many clusters would you suggest?
Maybe unsurprisingly we would suggest the same number as what we saw before.
So that's right, we can see the data was four clusters,
oh, pharaoh is very happy.
We can see a strong leveling off after four clusters.
Then this is just a cell for you to write your answer.
I would suggest four, great.