You now have seen in the main ideas associated and working with k-means.
From understanding clustering as an unsupervised approach,
to choosing the appropriate number of clusters.
But how do we actually build an algorithm that
figures out where the cluster centers are for these clusters?
Let's take a closer look at how this works.
Let's use this plot as an example,
and go step-by-step through how the k-means algorithm works.
When we start out,
we just have clusters of points with no groupings.
We start k-means by randomly placing k points onto our plot,
where k is the number of clusters you want to end up with.
We call each of these k points a centroid.
They're just randomly placed amongst the data,
so we need to move them.
The way we do this is to assign each point in our dataset to the closest centroid.
Now that we know which points belong in each group,
we move the centroid to the center of these points.
Once the centroid has moved,
points may be closer to the centroid of a different group.
Now, we will calculate the distance from each point to each centroid,
and again assign each point to the closest centroid.
With this new assignment of points,
we will again want to move the centroids to
the middle of the group of the points assigned to it.
This process will continue until the centroids no longer move.
This ends our search.
Here we have these k groups of clusters as our final results.