Welcome to this lesson on Principal Component Analysis or PCA.
The techniques you've seen so far in
this lesson had been about clustering your data together.
This begins our journey on unsupervised learning techniques aimed at transforming data,
rather than clustering it.
The main use of transformation techniques like
PCA is that it allows you to retain the informative parts of your data,
but with less of it.
Let's say you ask me,
"Hey, what do you have for breakfast today?"
I could say, "So,
I was running late,
I was going to grab a Nutrigain Bar,
but then I noticed I was all out.
So, I stopped by the coffee shop,
and I grabbed a coffee,
and then I was a little hungry,
so I also grabbed a pastry."
Alternatively, I could condense the answer to,
I had a coffee and a pastry.
The information needed to answer the question is available in both.
But the second, pulls the necessary information from the first.
This is how Principal Component Analysis works.
PCA is the first of the techniques we will look at that uses what it knows about
your data set to reduce it to only the parts that contain the most information.