There are a number of different use cases for PCA.
You work through one example,
where you reduce the dimensionality of image data to just over 10 features,
while still maintaining almost the same accuracy as when all the pixels were kept.
PCA can be used anytime you want to reduce the dimensionality of your data or find
latent features that might encapsulate a number of other features into a single factor.
Other specific situations of this include reducing the dimensionality of
high-dimensional microarray data or finding latent features
related to survey data that can help find patterns and behavioral habits.
As more and more data are created,
from YouTube videos, to car sensors,
to text messages this technique can help transform data
down in a way that helps maximize the information from the original data.