In this lesson, we introduced a new type of
unsupervised learning that doesn't involve clustering your data,
but rather transforming it.
You learned about PCA as a method to find
the directions of maximum variance in your data.
These are called Principal Components.
You applied this technique to handwritten digits using scikit-learn to reduce
the dimensionality of the images while still
being able to predict what number was written.
Finally, we discussed the importance of this technique in other applications.
Before moving on to the next lesson,
you'll do one more example of PCA,
where you can try this technique out on a dataset about different vehicles.
Though the dataset isn't really large enough to warrant the use of PCA,
the goal is more to get additional practice
before implementing this technique in the project. Enjoy.