The math behind principal components is largely based
on linear algebra and can be pretty confusing the first time you see it.
In this lesson, you'll see how PCA works
conceptually and I'll also show you how it works in code using scikit-learn.
People's knowledge of PCA is similar to people's knowledge in cars.
Most people know how to drive and basically know how a car works,
but few people know how the engine,
or the brake system work.
The goal of this lesson is to get you to the level of
mastery with PCA of an everyday user.
We'll teach you an overview of how PCA works,
how to use PCA within scikit-learn,
and how to interpret the results.
If you're interested in learning what's happening under the hood,
we provided additional links to learn PCA more in-depth.