You now have an idea
of how the many features of a survey or home,
can actually fall into just a few main buckets.
Because these buckets are explicitly in the data,
we call them latent features.
So the question is,
how do we actually take all of the data we have from all of these features and
condense it to only a few number of features that hold the most amount of information?
One option, is that we could just choose a subset of the features for each
latent variable that best captures the essence of that latent variable.
Maybe the square footage of the home.
Best captures the latent variable related to
home size and we could drop these other features related to the number of bedrooms,
the number of bathrooms, garages, etc.
We could perhaps do this with the other latent features as well,
but it seems like we're losing a lot of
potentially helpful information by simply dropping all of these features.
There has to be a better way we can reduce the number of
features in our dataset without simply dropping all of them.
Well, in fact there is a way we can preserve
more of the information and one of the main methods for doing this, is PCA.
The very topic of this lesson.