So far, you've been introduced to the idea of latent features,
which are topics or new features
that encompass many of the original features in your data set.
It would be nice, if we could transform our existing features to
best mapped the latent features and retain the most information,
rather than just dropping features and
losing information that might exist in those drop features.
With this in mind,
one of the main use cases of principal component analysis,
is to reduce the number of features in our dataset in just this way.
These new latent features that are created as a mix of
the original features are called principal components.
So the question is,
how do we combine the existing features to retain the most information?
To understand this, consider this plot that shows the relationship
between the number of rooms in a home and the square footage in a house.
In this example, if we were to reduce this two-dimensional data to one dimension,
we could do it by shrinking these points into this line.
At this point, you might think this looks a lot like regression.
Actually the first principal component of a dataset,
does have a lot in common with the models you create and regression,
but the goal here is not to make a prediction,
but to shrink the space that our data lives in.
So the ending goal is very different.
The goal here is to reduce this two-dimensional data to a single dimension,
represented by this line,
while the goal and regression is to predict one variable based on another.