Another question you might
have at this point is why did you choose to shrink the points into this line?
Why not a line that looks like this?
For that, we need to understand a bit more about how we choose principal components.
The principle components of a dataset have two properties,
the first property is that you want the components to
capture the largest amount of variance in the dataset.
By choosing components that span the largest variance in the dataset,
you lose the least amount of information.
Visually, you can understand the amount of information that is lost
by looking at the distance from each of the points to the component.
So from our dataset,
let's say we consider these two components the information lost for moving
the data to this component can be seen as the sum of these distances.
If we stack them together,
this is how much information is lost.
Alternatively, let's consider this component.
The amount of information lost,
can be visualized as the sum of these distances.
If we compare the amount of information lost,
we can see that this component loses less information.
The second thing that needs to be true about
our components is that they must be orthogonal to one another.
What exactly does this mean?
So this might take a little review of linear algebra,
but I'll explain the essence of the idea here.
Orthogonal components are those that have 90 degree angles with one another.
These two components here are orthogonal.
Alternatively, two components that do not have
90 degree angles between them are not orthogonal, like these here.
Though all of the examples you've seen so far have been
a two-dimensional data when performing PCA in practice,
it's more likely that you will have many many more dimensions to your data.
Therefore, having the ability to use scikit-learn
to perform these operations will be our next task.
I'll show you how to perform
these operations and then you'll put them to use on your own.