PCA is commonly used with high-dimensional data.
One type of high-dimensional data is images.
In this example, we'll look at a very common case using handwritten digit.
A classic example of image data is the MNIST dataset which was
open sourced in the late 1990s by researchers across Microsoft, Google and NYU.
I've linked more about this dataset in the information below, in the workbook.
To get started, let's import the libraries we'll need,
then it's important for us to read in the dataset.
In this case, we'll read in 42 thousand images which are in the training dataset.
The test dataset contains
an additional 28 thousand images that we won't work with quite yet,
then we could look at the header of the dataset.
We also might look at the description.
So in this case, we can see that there's a label column with the handwritten digits.
So, this is a image of a one this is an image of a zero,
an image of a one, an image of a four.
Then as you look through the sides,
there are values between zero and 255 to indicate
how much ink was in a particular pixel of the image and looking at the description,
it looks like there's some missing values in these last ones.
So, I'm just going to fill those with zero for now.
It looks like they're in some corner part of the pixels.
Given what we know about the data,
let's split the label off and put the images in their own matrix.
So here I've pulled off the label.
Now let's take a look at what the images look like with this little helper function.
You can get this helper function from the notebook pin below this video.
By passing in 100, I'm saying,
can you show me the first 100 images?
If we look at this,
there are some images that are really easy to see what values they are.
This looks like a one,
a zero, clearly an eight a nine.
But then there are other images that look like this,
what value might this be and what about this one here, what's this value?
There's another helper function that allow us to
look at the first 50 images of any type of number.
Again, you can grab this in the workbook below.
So using this function,
we can pass in the digit that we want to see and they will allow
us to take a look at the first 50 images of that particular digit.
So here, you can see the first 50 ones.
That's what this digit that we saw earlier actually is and look at this one here.
Some of these look like they'll be pretty easy to
predict using a machine-learning algorithm.
But others of them are certainly more difficult.
To take a first pass at predicting these.
There's another helper function that I wrote that'll
allow you to pass these to a random forest algorithm.
Using the random_forest_classifier function,
that's in the notebook below.
You can see that it's splitting your dataset into training and test sets.
Instantiating your RandomForestClassifier, fitting it to
the training dataset and then predicting on the test dataset.
Then it's building a confusion_matrix of the following results.
Let's take a look at how well it does.
So, anything along the diagonal is basically
something where we predicted the same value that was actually true,
and any of these values in the off-diagonal,
is something where we predicted a value that wasn't true.
You can see that almost 94% of the time,
we can predict the value correctly using all of the pixels in those images.
Here you can see that the dark blue indicates there are
very few images that were mislabeled on either side of the off-diagonal.
These elements along the diagonal indicate that there are
really high numbers associated with the values being correctly predicted.
So we can see that we can predict really well by using all the pixels,
but I wonder if we can use principal component analysis to create
a fewer number of features and still be able to predict with the same level of accuracy.
To do this, there's an additional helper function that performs PCA with your dataset.
So the do_pca function takes certain number of components and your dataset,
it fits the PCA and then gives you
back the X Matrix with that reduced number of features,
as well as the PCA model that you fit.
To begin with, let's try creating just two additional features.
So I'll pass in the two features as well as the X Matrix,
which is all of our pixels and then it'll give me back a PCA object.
So I'll call this just pca and it'll give me an X Matrix associated with RPCA.
So using the do_pca function,
you can see that it takes a number of components,
as well as the input data,
the features of your dataset and then what it returns is the PCA object
itself as well as a DataFrame of the transformed features.
So, using this, we can do give me back the pca and
the X_pca components and perform PCA on.
Let's say we want two components back and perform it on the X Matrix of our dataset.
So, the DataFrame that we get back,
if we look at the X_pca component is the same number of rows.
But you can see that it only has two columns,
which is a lot different than the original which had the same number of rows
but 784 pixels in the DataFrame for each image.
So let's try again using the same machine-learning algorithm we did up here,
the random forest classifier,
we can see how well we're able to predict the digits with only two of the features.
Let's try this. So, the X that we'll use is the X_pca and then we'll predict y.
Cool, so you can see that it performs
much worse than the previous example where we only get
35% of the digits correctly classified and via the matrix you can see down here.
Really, the only thing we're predicting very well at all is
the ones and everything else is pretty bad, sevens are okay.
But we're not getting a lot of features from this.
In order to better see how the components are separating out the handwritten digits,
let's use the plot_components function.
So, an ideal case would be if we plotted all the values,
but then our plot would be pretty overwhelming.
So what I'm gonna do is just take the first 100 and you can see here,
that it does a pretty good job of separating out those zeros,
as well as separating out the sevens.
But everything else is kind of clumped together,
this is an indication of exactly what we saw in this confusion matrix up here.