In the previous video,
you saw an example of working with the MNIST digits data.
A link to that dataset can be found here.
First, it's important to load the necessary libraries.
Then, we'll work through a number of questions.
The first thing to notice is that there's a bunch
of stuff loaded from this helper functions library.
These are essentially a number of functions that you saw in the previous video,
as well as some additional things.
We'll see throughout this notebook.
So, the first thing we need to do is use pandas to read in the dataset,
you can see that it's found at this link here.
You can also take a look at the data by doing a head, tail,
describe, info et cetera to see what it looks and make sure you're comfortable.
Similar to the previous video let's create a vector called y that holds
the label and store all the rest of the pixels in
x. I'm also going to do a fillna with zero like we saw in the previous video, great.
So, it looks like that checks out.
Now, use the show images by digit function from the helper functions to look at the ones,
two, threes or any other value.
By running this this should show us all of the twos in the dataset.
If we change that, we can take a look at the ones.
We could also look at say the eights.
Now that we have had a chance to look through the data,
let's try using this four-step process to fit
a model and score our model by predicting the digits.
So, the model that was used in the previous video,
was just via this function here.
This fit random forest classifier.
But you could also try to grid search and find a better model than this one.
We need to do an in-place equals true to
make sure that the data set actually came out okay.
Then, so here you can see an example of how well our model performs.
Again, around that 94 percent mark you saw in the previous video.
So, the purpose of this entire lesson is to look at PCA.
To replicate the process that you saw in the previous video,
you can use to do-PCA function that was created.
If we run this you can see that it takes in two inputs,
the number of components and the dataset that you
want to move into a fewer number of components.
Then the output is the PCA model as well as
the dataset created by creating a fewer number of features,
it takes the number of features.
I create a model using just two features in the previous video,
but you could try something with more if you wanted to.
We'll pass in our x matrix and then the two things that we get back are
the PCA object and the x matrix.
Now, we have back our PCA object and the reduced feature set down to only two.
The next thing that we can do,
is fit a random forest classifier.
This was one of the functions that was created in the previous video.
You can see that it takes in an x and y and
it prints the confusion matrix and the accuracy.
So, in this case you can see that it doesn't perform very well.
At least not in comparison to the model that uses all of the features.
In the next part we want to see if we can find a reduced number of
features that still allows for an accuracy of greater than 90 percent.
So, let's do four features,
let's just say we start at well we know not to.
So, maybe three maybe we go to like 15.
Sorry I skipped number seven.
So, the next thing we can do is use
the plot components function that you saw on the video,
to see how well the separation works.
So, this is exactly what we saw before.
Now, let's go a little bit further.
In this case we want to see if we can get better separation.
Specifically we want to get better than a 90 percent accuracy with
a fewer number of features than using of 700 plus of them.
Let's first just start out with a range from three to 15.
We can always make that higher later if we need to.
So, I'm going to pass that to the do PCA part.
So, do PCA is actually a function from here.
So, the nice part is that it's not only
printing the accuracy but it also returns the accuracy.
We can tell that because it's next to the outer portion here.
So, for each number of features between three and 15,
what we wanna do is run the do PCA algorithm which will give us back
PCA and the x matrix.
Then what we want to do with that is run the random forest classifier which is this part.
The random forest classifier takes in the x and the y.
So, x PCA and y.
They actually returns the accuracy.
So, we can tell that it returns the accuracy because
of this part right here being returned in the out.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create an empty list called ACCS.
Then what I want to do is append to that list the accuracy from each of these models.
Then I'm also going to create num features outside of that loop as a list, great.
So, this is going to create a whole bunch of these.
So, this is what happens with three features you
can see we get an accuracy of around 54 percent.
Then with four features we get an accuracy around 67 percent.
Then with five features we get 72 percent or so.
Then, around six we get close to 80 percent.
You can see we're starting to level off a little bit.
Then, we get 84, 85,
86 and it looks like it's done running.
So, with 14 features we're up to almost 88 percent.
It looks like we need to go just a little bit higher than that.
So, what I'll do is I'll start at 15 and go to maybe let's say 20 features, okay.
So, with 15 we have 90, were so close.
But it probably would have been smarter to build than a break.
Where we break if the accuracy of this model,
so if we stored this accuracy and then just appended it afterwards.
So, we said like at equals this and then append
the accuracy and then break if acc greater than 0.9.
This probably would've been the smartest way to do it and then just run
it from 15 to, all right.
I mean now we can do it to 100.
But it probably smarter to start at 20.
This part doesn't mean anything down here now.
So, at 20 we have an accuracy of around 90,
it's going back down. There we go.
Now, if we look at insert a cell below, we do print.
We can just look at CCS.
There's 11 of them.
So, you can see that we did 11, yeah.
So, from 20 to 30.
So, basically once we had 30 features that was enough to
understand the digits well enough to predict better than a 90 percent accuracy.
Which is a really big reduction from the 700 plus features that we had before.
It is possible that the extra features actually contribute to overfitting.
Then, this asked do you have evidence that this is happening for this dataset.
In the solution file that you can find in this notebook.
It looks at the range at a pretty wide range,
the suggestion is to look only below 100 components.
So, what we could do is basically run this for 100 components.
Then, plot the accuracy over a number of components and see if it starts dipping or not.
Or CFR model fits well.
But essentially that looks like the same processes up here.