So, let's do some math.
Let's assign to each data point an initial weight of one.
Now, let's fit our first Learner.
Before we wanted to minimize the number of errors.
Now we want to minimize the sum of weights of
the incorrectly classified points which as of now is the same.
So, here is the model.
If we add the weights of the correctly classified points,
we get a seven and three for the incorrectly classified points.
So, let's weigh the incorrectly classified points a bit more.
How much? Well, let's make it enough to have this model be a 50-50 model.
So, if we take these three points and weight them by a factor of 7/3 three or 2.33,
that our model now has seven as the sum of the weights of
the correctly classified points and also
seven as the sum of the weights of the incorrectly classified points.
So, this model now is lame, and we need a second one.
Our second model will be this one which fits the newly weighted data best.
For this one, we can see that if we add the weights of the correctly classified points,
we get 11 and for the incorrectly classified ones we get three again.
So, let's weigh the incorrectly classified points.
By how much? Well, enough to make this model a 50-50 model again.
Notice that if we weighed this three errors each one by a factor of 11/3 or 3.66,
now the sum of the weights of the incorrectly classified points is 11.
So, our model is just a 50-50 model again. That's lame.
Let's fit a third model in this newly weighted data.
Here is our third model.
Now, what is the added weight of the correctly classified points.
Now it's 19 and still three for the incorrect ones.
We can keep this going, but let's stop.
We have built three models and here are the three models or weak learners that we built.
In the next video, we will learn how to combine them.