Now, in order to combine models,
we'll actually weight them by how well they're doing.
In this way, if one of our friends just answers the questions better,
we'll believe that friend more.
So let's turn to a hypothetical question.
We have three friends.
One always tells the truth,
the other one tells the truth half of the time and lies half of the time,
and we don't know which half,
and the third one always lies.
The question is, which one of these three is the one that we should ignore the most?
Equivalently, here we have three models.
The first one is always correct,
the second one is correct half of the time,
and the third one is wrong every single time.
Which of these models is worse for us?
Try your answer below.