Current uses of machine learning
come from the combination of two perspectives.
One is the perspective of statisticians and the second is that of computer scientists.
The statisticians perspective has evolved from understanding data.
The field of data analysis was originally a field of mathematics based on questions like,
how do we better understand the mechanisms that create data?
From these questions, probability-based models were used to model the world around us.
For example, there's a distribution to model expected scores on a test,
number of daily incidence on a stretch of road,
or how frequently words show up in a body of text.
The derivation of distributions like these were
breakthroughs for mechanisms that could create data in the real world.
These mathematical functions were used to describe
essentially all aspects of our daily lives.
But as it turns out,
these models are an over-simplification
of the complexities that exists in the real world.
Often, the probability-based models that were created for a situation did not
do a very good job of simulating the actual data observed in the world.
In the next video,
you will see a different perspective,
that of a computer scientist.
The combination of the computer scientist and statistician viewpoints results
in the diverse techniques used in machine learning today.