In the 1950s, computer scientists were
coming to the realization that it might be best if they
didn't hard-code every decision a computer would
make as essentially never ending if-else statements,
rather computer should determine what was
best by looking at data and recognizing patterns.
This idea of recognizing patterns and
data is what is commonly recognized as machine learning.
Drawing from the world of statistics,
in order to avoid hard-coding rules,
these new techniques involved rules that were based on distributions.
But using statistical distributions as generators of data,
exposed pretty large discrepancies between the data
generated by our models and the data you actually obtained in the real rep.
Machine learning has continued to evolve into extremely flexible models based
more and more on data and less and less on human-enforced if-else statements.
These flexible models have been shown to predict better
than previous well-defined modeling techniques.
This leads to the current state of machine learning where prediction has become
key often creating extremely flexible and complex models.
These complex models outperform models that follow if-else statements set up by
humans as well as those that follow
distributions that are known as well-known probability distributions.
Unfortunately, these complex models often leave the why of a prediction unknown.
Though, these techniques might be able to identify tumors better than
doctors or play at a world-class level in the game of Go,
the individuals creating these models can't
always explain why they're making these decisions.