Machine learning has three main categories: supervised,
unsupervised, and reinforcement learning.
In supervised machine learning,
our algorithms learn from labeled data.
After studying the labeled data,
these techniques are able to determine which label should be given to
new data based on observing patterns and
associating those patterns to new unlabeled data.
Supervised learning can be divided into two categories: classification and regression.
Classification models predict a category that an item belongs to.
Many people believed that these models are used for
events with only two possible outcomes,
like whether an email is spam or not,
but most can actually be extended to predict any number of categories.
For example, there are classification techniques that allow us
to predict which of many breeds a dog belongs to.
Alternatively, regression models predict
a numeric value like home price or an individual's height.
You will learn about these techniques
in the supervised machine learning part of this program.