If you've been following
the headlines related to artificial intelligence and machine learning,
you probably have heard of deep learning.
Deep learning has beaten
essentially all other machine-learning algorithms in its ability to predict,
and it can actually be used for supervised,
unsupervised, and reinforcement learning.
From a historical perspective,
the growth of this technique makes a lot of sense.
Over time, we've cared less and less about how we make predictions,
and now we care more about the accuracy of our predictions.
This connects well to the advancement of deep learning where we rarely
understand all of how or why our model make certain predictions.
Unfortunately, deep learning is not the solution to every problem.
It has three major barriers to entry.
First, you must have enough data.
Deep learning requires a lot of data.
Second, you must have the computing power.
In order to reach superhuman performance in the game of Go,
Google's DeepMind AlphaGo required 1,202 CPUs and 176 GPUs.
Third, you probably won't understand why certain decisions were being made,
given the complexity and flexibility of these algorithms.
For these reasons, not every
application of machine learning is one that requires deep learning.
You'll be getting some practice using deep learning in this program.
However, we have an entire deep learning nanodegree program available on the subject.
So, it's not the primary focus of this program.