If you're interested in
solving machine learning questions that fall into either supervised,
or unsupervised learning, the most popular open-source
library in the world for solving these problems is scikit-learn.
Scikit-learn, provides any data scientist the ability to use
the most advanced techniques in supervised and unsupervised machine learning easily,
and for a variety of situations.
You can expect that scikit-learn will continue to
be used for machine learning in both industry,
and academia for the foreseeable future.
In the following lessons,
you will get comfortable solving a range of problems using this library.