Machine Learning Models have the power to summarize data efficiently and intelligently.
Unfortunately, since the data in our world often holds errors and biases,
the models we build will hold the same errors and biases.
As an example, imagine you want to build a model to predict
who the best candidate is for a job based on existing data.
If there were biases and historical hiring patterns based on gender, race, age,
economic status et cetera,
these biases are going to be held by any predictive model you build based on these data.
Unfortunately, the bias held by humans will
transfer to computers so long as humans are the creators of the data.
Images, text, speech, and video are
all data being ingested by computers in today's world to make data-based decisions.
But humans generate these data.
The potential biases in the data created as a result of
our human biases should always be on your mind when building your models.
Real-world validation of your models is even more important than statistical validation.