This lesson provided some more context as to the current state of machine learning,
and how it's evolved from the fields of statistics, and computer science.
You got to look at three branches of machine learning: supervised learning,
unsupervised learning, and reinforcement learning.
We also discussed at a high level
scikit-learn as a library in Python for machine learning,
and deep learning, as a popular technique currently leading the way.
You will get more experience with both of these in the material ahead.
Finally, we looked at the ethical challenges ahead of us in the field.
Now that you have an overview of the field,
it's time to dive more into the details.
First, Release will be showing you how
the most popular supervised learning techniques work. Let's get started.