I know how frustrating,
daunting, and in some cases,
demoralizing it is to have to go through
the whole process of creating an account and building the network.
It can be hard to put yourself out there.
Like many of you, I didn't see the value in investing
so much time and energy into nurturing my LinkedIn account,
but as I continued my job search,
I kept seeing how more and more potential employers
were asking for LinkedIn profile URLs.
Several of my applications could have been submitted solely on LinkedIn,
if I had wanted to do so,
yet still I resisted.
Almost an entire year later,
I was still actively looking for a job and was just about to the end of
my sanity when I finally stumbled across this role with Udacity.
I applied for this position and literally one day later received an email from
LinkedIn advertising the exact same position. I'm not alone.
According to Udacity's research,
one in four people don't network at all.
I am convinced that had I worked on my LinkedIn account more often,
I would have found this job sooner than I did.
Here at Udacity, we even did some research and found that
85% of job openings are filled through networking.
Eighty five percent, with recruiters relying more heavily on LinkedIn,
and the ease of creating quality networks that can
provide so much opportunity for growth and change,
having a LinkedIn profile can significantly
impact your job search and help you find your dream job.
So, take the opportunity to log in to linkedin.com and update your profile today.