Hello, I'm J. In this lesson,
we'll be talking about dimensionality reduction.
The first method we'll look at in this lesson is random projection,
which is a powerful dimensionality reduction method
that is computationally more efficient than PCA.
It is commonly used in cases where a dataset has
too many dimensions for PCA to be directly computed.
Let's say your application is running on a system with limited computational resources,
or you just find that PCA is too taxing for a specific situation that you're in.
Just like PCA, it takes a dataset.
Let's say this is our dataset with d dimensions,
let's say 1,000 and a certain number of samples or rows,
let's say n. These are columns.
So, it takes our dataset and it produces
a transformation of it that is in a much smaller number of columns.
So, okay, let's say 50 for example,
but the same number of samples and where your each column
here it captures information from multiple columns there.
Let's look at an oversimplified example for reducing
the dimensions of a dataset from two dimensions into one dimension.
PCA here will try to maximize variance.
So, it finds the vector or direction that maximizes the variance so it
loses the least amount of information when it
projects the data from two dimensions to one.
So, that line would be something like this,
and these would be the projections,
and so in one dimension,
the dataset would look like this.
Random projection, so with this calculation that PCA
did especially if you're talking about a lot of dimensions,
it consumes a certain amount of resources.
Random projection just say, pick a line,
any line, we'll do a projection on that, that's our dataset.
So, while it doesn't really make a lot of sense in
our over-simplified scenario like this from two dimensions to one,
it actually works and it works really well in higher dimensions,
and it works in a high-performance way.
The basic premise of a random projection is that we can
simply reduce the number of dimensions in our dataset,
by multiplying it by a random matrix like this.
So, d, we will have d in our dataset but k is something we either compute or it's
something that we desire and there is a way to compute what is
a conservative or a good estimate for k. So,
that would be the resulting dataset.
Just multiplying by a random matrix,
that's all random projection is in a way.
Let's take a concrete example here,
let's say this is our dataset,
and it has 12,000 dimensions,
that's our d, and it has 1,500 rows or samples.
If we give this to scikit-learn and say, okay, scikit-learn,
can you please do a random projection for this dataset just using your default values?
It will return this dataset for us which it will be in
6,200 dimensions and the same number of samples obviously.
So, how do we know that it works and where does the k come from?
The theoretical underpinning for random projection is this idea called
the Johnson-Lindenstrauss lemma which states
that a dataset of N points in high-dimensional space.
So, this dataset, N points,
high-dimensional space, 12,000 is pretty high.
It can be mapped.
Multiplying by this random matrix,
down to a space in much lower dimension which is this narrow dataset in a way.
This is why it's really important for us.
It can be done in a way that preserves
the distances between the points to a large degree.
So, the distances between each two points,
each pair of points in these datasets,
after projection that is preserved in a certain way.
That's really important because in most or
in a lot of supervised and unsupervised learning,
the algorithms really care about the distances between the points.
So, we have a set a level of guarantee that
these distances will be distorted a little bit but they can be preserved.
How can they be preserved?
What sort of guarantees we have?
Let's take a quick example and just actually calculate that out.
So, let's say we take these first two rows here,
so this one and this one,
the first two points in our dataset and then these are their values after projection.
So, the same samples but the different level of dimensionality.
So, what the Johnson-Lindentrauss lemma tells us that,
the distance between the two points in the projection squared is sort of squeezed.
So, it's larger than the distance between the two points in
the original dataset squared times one minus Epsilon.
So, epsilon is the level of error that we are
allowing the random projection to have in the projection.
So, the distance between the two points in
the projected data set will be larger than one minus Epsilon
times square of distance of the two points in the original dataset
and it will be smaller than one plus Epsilon off that distance squared.
I've actually calculated those numbers.
So, the distance between these two points is 125.6.
So, we put that in here.
Epsilon, the default value so we didn't change anything,
the default value in scikit-learn is 0.1.
It can take any value from 0-1.
So, if we do it like this,
the distance between these two points is 125.8.
So, this distance here will be larger than 0.9
times this distance and smaller than 1.1 times this distance squared.
So, you can see that Epsilon is like a liver.
It goes into the calculation of how many columns are produced,
and it is the level of error that we are allowing
the distortion to have this reduction of dimensionality.
So, this guarantee preserves the distance between every pair of points in the dataset.
So, it's not just one and two,
it's one and every other point,
and two and every other point.
So, that guarantee is there.
An Epsilon is just an input into the function that we can use
to say preserve the distances by this degree.