The implementation of random prediction in Scikit-learn is pretty straightforward.
So, we just import the library here and then we declare it.
Sparse random projection is the faster.
So, there is a Gaussian random projection,
there's sparse random projection.
This is a little bit more performant,
and then we fit transform,
pass it our data set, and then we get the new transformed dataset.
So, here if we want to declare or specify a specific value for Epsilon,
we pass it here, or if we want to force it into a specific size or number of components.
If we don't specify anything,
the number of components is automatic and it's calculated by using Epsilon,
and by using the number of points or samples in the dataset.
So, it will choose based on the dataset.