Welcome back. In this video,
we'll talk a little bit of the Independent Component Analysis Algorithm.
So, this is going to be a very high level view,
we'll not delve deep into the math.
We'll refer you to the right place,
but it's good and valuable that you know.
Let's have a general idea about how it works and
what assumptions are there when we want to use it.
So, the dataset that we have, we call X.
Right? So, that X was generated by multiplying.
What we would call a mixing matrix,
which is A by the source signals,
which we also don't have.
So, we don't have A, we don't have S. But,
S is what we want to calculate in the end.
So, if X is A times S, we can say that S,
which is the source goal of what we want here is W,
which is the inverse of A.
So, if A is the mixing matrix,
we can call W the unmixing the matrix,
times X times the dataset that we have,
the original recordings that we have.
So, this formula here.
So, X is an input that we have,
W is what we are trying to calculate,
S is the results.
So, the ICA algorithm in a process is all about approximating
W or finding the best W that we can multiply by X,
the dataset here to produce the original signals.
The ICA algorithm is explained clearly in
this paper called Independent Component Analysis: Algorithms and Applications.
It goes into the derivation of everything here.
It shows a couple of ways to calculate number of different parts of the algorithm,
but if we're to have a just a very high-level view of the algorithm called FastICA.
So, this is one way,
this is the one that's implemented actually in scikit-learn.
First, we have X which is our dataset.
We'll center it, we can whiten it, and then,
we will choose an initial random weights matrix.
We'll call that W. In third step,
we estimate W and W as a matrix contains vectors.
The number of vectors, each one is as a weight vector.
After we estimate it, we decorrelate it and the correlation is
to prevent W1 and W2 to convert to the same values.
So, we want them to converge to different values.
Then, we repeat from three, until we converge.
Until we find a value of W that we're satisfied with.
Most of them have comes at step number three here.
So, how does the estimation happen?
This is the formula for estimating each of the vectors here.
Where E is the expected value,
X is the dataset,
G is just some non-quadratic function.
We have the ability to choose a number of them.
What is commonly used,
what scikit-learn uses and what the paper proposes?
As one of the options is tanh,
a hyper tangent function and the decorrelation is calculated like this.
So, let's talk a little bit about this.
So, since it might seem a little bit cryptic.
So, ICA assumes a couple of things.
Right? It assumes that the components are statistically
independent and the paper explains a little bit what that means in statistical language.
It also assumes that components must have non-Gaussian distributions.
Non-Gaussianity is very important here.
It's actually the key to estimating ICA and without it,
we'll not be able to calculate,
we'll not be able to restore the original signals if they were Gaussian.
So, building from here,
the central limit theorem tells us that
the distribution of a sum of independent variables,
tends towards a Gaussian distribution.
So, knowing that, we take W,
this weight matrix here.
We take it to be a matrix that maximizes the non-Gaussianity of W transpose X.
So, non-Gaussianity strikes is here again.
But here, is exactly we have to calculate non-Gaussianity,
because that's the term that this entire algorithm tries to maximize.
So, what's one way to calculate non-Gaussianity?
This term here, is an approximation of something called negentropy.
Negentropy is comes from information theory,
where the idea of entropy comes from and this is a way to approximate it.
You don't need to know all these details,
as long as you know the assumptions of non-Gaussianity.
The independent components, they have to be independent or else I say,
we'll not be able to find them.
If you know these conditions,
and you know the situation where ICA needs to work, that's important.
If you want to know the details of and they look at the derivation,
that paper is link in the comments below and they description below the video.