In terms of applications,
ICA is widely used in medical scanners and so this is
an example of a type of brain scan called the EEG or MEG,
where each of these sensors detects electric signals or in a similar test,
magnetic signals inside the brain.
So, each of these is a electric sensor and each of them would produce these readings,
that are all mixtures of things happening inside the brain,
and so ICA can be used where these are the initial or actual readings of this data.
ICA is an algorithm that's able to look at them and then
find the independent components inside the brain that generated
these readings that are mixed here because
an electric signal will be generated in one part of
the brain bound to be hard to tell because you
have the skull separating the sensors from the actual places.
So, ICA is widely used in scenarios like this.
It's also used in FMRIs in the same way for a lot of brain scans.
So, these are the independent components and it can
isolates where certain signals came from in the brain.
There have been attempts at using ICA for financial data.
I don't know that this is a very popular thing to do,
but it's just interesting to look at, I guess.
So, this is one paper that tries to apply ICA to a factor model in finance, let's say.
So, this data is stocks signals and
it tries to isolate what caused the stocks to go up and down,
what components are there and most of
these papers they're trying to do ICA in finance they, something like this,
the economy is a very complex system,
and so, they rarely would come up with things that are of real value.
This could be interesting to look at, I guess.
There's another one looking at financial data as well,
and so this is a dataset of five stores and this is the cash flow of them.
So, this is a retail chain of some sort.
So, this is the cash flow over 140 weeks.
So, you see spikes and go up and they go down.
To make it a little bit more clear, let's break it down.
So, this is the first year,
this is the second year,
and this is a part of the third year that is available.
So, you can see dip here our spike and then a dip.
This is about Christmas time, I guess.
So, if we do, I say to this,
we get these four components.
They would give some indication of things that are happening.
So, this first component captures this dries,
the spike and dip in Christmas, for example.
In this fourth one captures during the summer month,
there seems to be a bit of a slump here.
So, this is another thing that I thought is interesting to look at.
There aren't on lot of papers or applications of using ICA in financial data,
but it could be intriguing and these papers are linked in the text below.