So, let's start with an example.
Let's say we're in charge of writing
the recommendation engine for the App Store or for Google play.
Our task is to recommend to people the app they're most likely to download,
and we should do this based on previous data.
Our previous data is this table with six people each in a row,
and the columns are their gender, male or female,
their occupation, work or study,
and the app they downloaded.
The options for the app are Pokemon Go, WhatsApp, and Snapchat.
So, the model we'll create will take the first two columns and guess the third one.
So let's start with some small quizzes to test our intuition with this data.
The first quiz is the following: if we have a woman who works at an office,
what app should we recommend to her,
Pokemon Go, WhatsApp, or Snapchat?
The second quiz is the following: if we have a man who works at a factory,
what app should we recommend to him?
And the third one says, if we have a girl
who's in high school, what app do we recommend to her?
Enter your answers below.