Well, let's try both.
The best horizontal line would be somewhere around here.
It does an okay job, but it doesn't really separate the points that well,
at least a lot of blue points in the red area and vice versa.
So, what happens if we try a vertical line?
Well, it seems that the best cut is here around five.
That does a pretty good job and only leaves
five red points on the blue side and five blue points on the red side.
So, let's go for that one,
and our answer is vertical line.
This means that the best feature to separate this data is test,
and the best threshold is five.
Therefore, we can add our first node to the decision tree and this node asks,
"Is your test greater than or equal to five or is it less than five?"
And now, we can do even more.
We can try dividing each of the two halves with a horizontal line,
which is the equivalent of saying, "Okay.
I've seen your tests.
Now, let's see how you did in the grades."
The left half can be cut with a vertical line over here at height seven.
This means, if your test score is less than five,
then you need seven or more in the grades to get accepted,
otherwise, you get rejected.
The right half can be separated with a vertical line at height two.
This means, if your test score is greater than or equal to five,
then you need to have two or more in your grades in order to get accepted,
otherwise, you get rejected.
So, we've built our Decision Tree in a similar way as before,
except now at each node,
we don't have a yes/no question,
but we have a threshold which would cut the values in two.