So we had a question we're trying to answer and the question is,
how do we find this line that separates
the blue points from the red points in the best possible way?
Let's answer this question by first looking at
a small example with three blue points and three red points.
And we're going to describe an algorithm that will find
the line that splits these points properly.
So the computer doesn't know where to start.
It might as well start at a random place by picking a random linear equation.
This equation will define a line and
a positive and negative area given in blue and red respectively.
What we're going to do is to look at how badly this line
is doing and then move it around to try to get better and better.
Now the question is,
how do we find how badly this line is doing?
So let's ask all the points.
Here we have four points that are correctly classified.
They are these two blue points in the blue area and these two red points in the red area.
And these points are correctly classified,
so they say, "I'm good."
And then we have these two points that are incorrectly classified.
That's this red point in the blue area and this blue point in the red area.
We want to get as much information from them so we want them
to tell us something so that we can improve this line.
So what is it that they can tell us?
So here we have a misclassified point,
this red point in the blue area.
Now think about this.
If you were this point,
what would you tell the line to do?
Would you like it to come closer to you or farther from you?
That's our quiz.
Will the misclassified point want the line to come closer to it or farther from it?