So we're still in our quest for an algorithm that will help
us pick the best model that separates our data.
Well, since we're dealing with probabilities then let's use them in our favor.
Let's say I'm a student and I have two models.
One that tells me that my probability of getting accepted is
80% and one that tells me the probability is 55%.
Which model looks more accurate?
Well, if I got accepted then I'd say
the better model is probably the one that says 80%.
What if I didn't get accepted?
Then the more accurate model is more likely the one that says 55 percent.
But I'm just one person. What if it was me and a friend?
Well, the best model would more likely be the one that
gives the higher probabilities to the events that happened to us,
whether it's acceptance or rejection.
This sounds pretty intuitive.
The method is called maximum likelihood.
What we do is we pick the model that gives the existing labels the highest probability.
Thus, by maximizing the probability,
we can pick the best possible model.