So a quick recap. We have two models,
the bad one on the left and the good one on the right.
And the way to tell they're bad or good is to calculate
the probability of each point being the color it is according to the model.
Multiply these probabilities in order to obtain the probability of
the whole arrangement and then check that the model on
the right gives us a much higher probability than the model on the left.
Now all we need to do is to maximize this probability.
But probability is a product of numbers and products are hard.
Maybe this product of four numbers doesn't look so scary.
But what if we have thousands of datapoints?
That would correspond to a product of thousands of numbers,
all of them between zero and one.
This product would be very tiny,
something like 0.0000 something and we definitely want to stay away from those numbers.
Also, if I have a product of thousands of numbers and I change one of them,
the product will change drastically.
In summary, we really want to stay away from products.
And what's better than products?
Well, let's ask our friend here.
Products are bad, but sums are good. Let's do sums.
So let's try to turn these products into sums.
We need to find a function that will help us turn products into sums.
What would this function be?
It sounds like it's time for a quiz.
Quiz. Which function will help us out here?
Sine, cosine, logarithm or the exponential function?
Enter your answer below.