So let's study gradient descent in more mathematical detail.
Our function is a function of the weights and it can be graph like this.
It's got a mathematical structure so it's not Mt.
Everest anymore, it's more of a mount Math-Er-Horn.
So we're standing somewhere in Mount Math-Er-Horn and we need to go down.
So now the inputs of the functions are W1 and W2 and the error function is given by
E. Then the gradient of E is given by
the vector sum of the partial derivatives of E with respect to W1 and W2.
This gradient actually tells us the direction we want to
move if we want to increase the error function the most.
Thus, if we take the negative of the gradient,
this will tell us how to decrease the error function the most.
And this is precisely what we'll do.
At the point we're standing,
we'll take the negative of the gradient of the error function at that point.
Then we take a step in that direction.
Once we take a step,
we'll be in a lower position.
So we do it again, and again,
and again, until we are able to get to the bottom of the mountain.
So this is how we calculate the gradient.
We start with our initial prediction Y had equals sigmoid of W Expo's B.
And let's say this prediction is bad because
the error is large since we're high up in the mountain.
The prediction looks like this,
Y had equal sigmoid of W 1 x 1 plus all the way to WnXn plus b.
Now the error function is given by the formula we saw before.
But what matters here is the gradient of the error function.
The gradient of the error function is precisely the vector formed by
the partial derivative of the error function with respect to the weights and the bias.
Now, we take a step in the direction of the negative of the gradient.
As before, we don't want to make any dramatic changes,
so we'll introduce a smaller learning rate alpha.
For example, 0.1.
And we'll multiply the gradient by that number.
Now taking the step is exactly the same thing as
updating the weights and the bias as follows.
The weight Wi will now become Wi prime.
Given by Wi minus alpha times the partial derivative of the error,
with respect to Wi.
And the bias will now become b prime given by b minus
alpha times partial derivative of the error with respect to b.
Now this will take us to a prediction with a lower error function.
So, we can conclude that the prediction we have now with weights W prime b prime,
is better than the one we had before with weights W and b.
This is precisely the gradient descent step.