So, let's go back to this example of where we saw
some data that is not linearly separable.
So a line can not divide these red and blue points and we looked at some solutions,
and if you remember, the one we considered more seriously was this curve over here.
So what I'll teach you now is to find this curve and it's very similar than before.
We'll still use grading dissent.
In a nutshell, what we're going to do is for
these data which is not separable with a line,
we're going to create a probability function where the points in the blue region are more
likely to be blue and the points in the red region are more likely to be red.
And this curve here that separates them is
a set of points which are equally likely to be blue or red.
Everything will be the same as before except this equation
won't be linear and that's where neural networks come into play.