Now, I want to apply the Naive Bayes algorithm.
We want to calculate the probability that an email is
spam given that it contains the word easy and money.
As we briefly stated before, we'll make an assumption.
We'll assume that the product of the probabilities that the email is
spam if it contains the word easy times the probability that it's spam.
If it contains the word money is the desired probability.
This is a Naive assumption because it could be that these two are not independent.
Say it could be that emails containing the word
easy are more likely to contain the word money.
But it turns out that this assumption ends up
working really well in many situations, so we'll make it.
So, we obtain that the probability of the email being
spam is one-half times two-thirds which is one-third.
For clarity, written the actual formula for
these two calculations using Bayes theorem that we've done previously.
These two give us again 0.5 and 0.67 for the posteriors.
So finally, we multiply them and obtain the probability of an email being
spam given that it has the words easy and money is 0.33.
In general, this is what happens.
Let's say we have N suspicious words.
For example, easy, money, cheap, et cetera.
These are our conditions,
and we get a new email we tested against them.
So, we make the Naive assumption that the probability of spam given
that the email contains all these words is the product of these probabilities.
How do we calculate each one of them?
Easy. Using Bayes theorem.