Okay, so quick recap.
Here, we have a very easy classification problem with blue and red points.
On our model, we'll just make a cut here.
As a matter of fact, the SVM model will make this
cut with two lines that maximize this margin,
separating the points as much as possible.
But let's get a bit more complicated.
What about this arrangement of points?
All of a sudden, a line won't cut it.
What we need is a more complex model. Well, here's an idea.
Our points are in a line,
but here we see them on a plane.
Let's exploit that.
Let's switch from a one-dimensional problem, the line,
to a two-dimensional problem,
the plane, by adding a y axis.
And now, let's use a parabola.
Let's draw the function y equals x squared.
And now, let's lift every point to its corresponding place in the parabola.
All of a sudden, our points are nicely separable because now,
using the original SVM algorithm,
we can find a good cut.
Let's say it's this line,
the line y equals four.
So, now the question is,
how do we bring this back to the line and find the boundary there?
Well, very simple, our original equation is y equals x squared.
Our line is y equals four.
How did these two combine?
Well, by equating them,
we get x squared equals four.
That's our new equation.
And what is x squared equals four?
That factors into two linear polynomials with solutions x
equals two and x equals minus two.
So, those will make our boundary.
And now magic, we bring this down to the line again and we have our x
equals two and our x equals minus two as the boundaries for this model.
Notice that they split the data really well.
The trick is known as the Kernel Trick and it's widely used in Support Vector Machines,
as well as many other algorithms in machine learning.