Now, let's see how the kernel method works in higher dimensions.
Here, we still want to draw a mountain at every point.
In the 3D case, this mountain is a Gaussian paraboloid and it lifts the points like this.
Then if you want to separate the point from the rest,
we can cut it with a plane.
The plane will intersect the paraboloid at
a circle and this circle is what will become our boundary.
So if we have more points, we'd do the same.
We use a similar method than before to find the right weights for the combination of
mountains that will bring the majority of
the red points up while keeping the majority of the blue points down.
And then we cut this with the plane.
When we project down,
then the intersections of the curve on the plane will
give us the boundaries that will split our data.