So, if you said the line on the left, you are correct.
Because as you can see,
the yellow line is pretty well-spaced
between the blue points and the red points, whereas,
the green line is not,
because it's a little too close to some of the points on both sides.
And how can we see this? Well, we look at
all the distances between the closest point to one
of the lines and compare them to
the distances between the closest points to the other line.
So, the closest point to the yellow line is this one and
the closest point to the green line is this one over here.
And then, we check, which one of these closest points is actually farther from the line?
So, we compare these two distances and we see
that the one on the left is bigger, so that line wins.
In a nutshell, this is how an SVM works.
But throughout this lesson, I'll be showing you this algorithm in more detail.