Now, we have learned precision and recall.
So, as we've seen, our medical model has a precision of
55.7 percent and a recall of 83.3 percent.
It's supposed to be a high recall model.
And our spam detector has a precision of 76.9 percent and a recall of 37 percent,
and is supposed to be a high precision model.
Now, the question is, do we want to be carrying two numbers around all the time?
Do we want to carry precision in one pocket and recall in the other one?
And I will be looking at both any time we make a decision.
Well, that's inconvenient. We kind of want to only have one score.
So the question is, how do we combine these two scores into one?
Can we think of a way? Well, a pretty simple ways taking the average.
So let's take the average of precision and recall.
In the left, we get 69.5 percent.
Then in the right, we get 56.95 percent.
And that's an okay metric.
But I'm sure you're probably thinking in your head,
that's not very different than accuracy.
That's not saying too much.
And the way to see how this average is not
the best idea is to try it in the extreme example.
So the credit card fraud example.
So, again, we have a bunch of good and fraudulent credit card transactions.
Now let's pick a terrible model one which says,
"All transactions are good."
So what is the precision of this model?
Well, the precision is, out of the ones we classified as bad,
how many of them are bad?
That's a question about number because we didn't label anything as fraudulent.
So it's kind of zero divided by zero, which is undefined.
But it makes sense to think of it as
100 percent since we made zero mistakes among the ones who predicted positive,
which is what precision tries to measure.
So let's say this model has 100 percent precision.
Now, as for the recall, the recall is,
how many of the fraudulent transactions did we catch?
Well, since we caught none,
this number is zero.
So the average between precision and recall is
50 percent since it's the average of 100 and zero.
Now the question is, do I want to give this horrendous model of 50 percent?
It seems like a really high score for such a lousy model.
I kind of want to give it a much lower score, perhaps even zero.
For average is not that good. Now let's try the opposite.
And let's try the model that says that all transactions are fraudulent.
What is the precision of this model?
Well, out of all the transactions that I said are fraudulent,
472 were actually fraudulent.
So, the precision is 472 divided by 284,807,
which is 0.16 percent.
And the recall is actually pretty good,
because out of the 472 fraudulent transactions, I caught all of them.
So the recall is 472 divided by 472, which is 100 percent.
So, again, the average of the two is the average of 0.16 and 100, which is 50.08.
Again, a very high score for a really lousy model.
So we want to give it a lower score or maybe something close to zero.
So, in summary, average is not the greatest thing
in principle if either precision or recall is very low.
We want the number to be low even if the other one is high.
So, here's a solution.
There's another type of average called the harmonic mean,
and it works as follows.
Let's say we have two numbers,
X and Y. X is smaller than Y.
And we have their arithmetic mean over here.
That is the average,
X plus Y divided by two.
And we have something called the harmonic mean which is defined
by 2XY divided by X plus Y.
And it's kind of an average two in the sense that if the two numbers are equal,
we get X or Y,
and it always lies between X and Y.
But actually, it's a mathematical fact that
the harmonic mean is always less than the arithmetic mean.
So it's closer to the smaller number than to the higher number.
So let's look at an example. If the precision is one and the recall is zero,
the average is 0.5,
but the harmonic mean is,
if we plug in the formula, zero.
Another example, if the precision is 0.2 and the recall is 0.8,
then the arithmetic mean is 0.5,
but the harmonic mean is 0.32.
So it's closer to the lower number.
So, from now on, we will not be using the average or arithmetic mean,
but we'll be using the harmonic mean,
and that's going to be called F1 score.
And as we said, the F1 score is closer to the smallest,
between precision and recall.
So if one of them is particularly low,
the F1 score kind of raises a flag.
The average kind of says, "If one is good,
but the other one is bad,
then the average is okay."
But the F1 score raises the flag if one of them is small.
So we can now go back to the credit card fraud example and calculate the F1 score.
Since is going to be the harmonic mean between the precision,
which is 100 percent,
and the recall, which is zero,
we can plug in the formula and actually get an F1 score of zero.
This is much closer to what the models should score.
So, in the following two quizzes,
we'll let you calculate the F1 score of the medical model and the spam email model.