So to summarize, this is how I see machine learning.
We have a problem to solve which is represented by this broken car over
here and we have some tools to fix it which are the algorithms of machine learning.
Finally, you have some measurement tools,
which we then use to measure each tool's performance.
Then you pick the best tool to fix your car.
To be more specific in machine learning you have
a problem which is some data you need to classify.
You also have a bunch of algorithms things like neural networks,
logistic regression, polynomial regression as VMs, decision trees,
random forests et cetera and we have a bunch of metrics,
things like model complexity graphs,
accuracy precision, recall, F1 score,
learning curves et cetera.
What you do, is you use these ones to test your models,
see how they're doing, pick the best one and that's what you use to model your data.
Then when you have a new point,
you can predict it's label based on that model.
That's it. That's how you test,
evaluate and validate models.