So let's see. The true positives are the points that
are positive and the model correctly labels as positive.
These are the six blue points over here.
The true negatives are the points that are
negative and the model correctly labels as negative.
These are the five negative red points over here.
The false positives are the points that are negative
but the model incorrectly labels as positive.
These are these two red points over here.
And finally, the false negatives are the points that
are positive but the model incorrectly labels as negative.
That's just this blue point over here.
So there we go. That's the confusion matrix.