Now, we'll study one of the ways to measure how good a model is,
called that the accuracy.
The accuracy is the answer to the question,
"Out of all the patients, how many did we classify correctly?"
The answer is, the ratio between the number of
correctly classified points and the number of total points.
In this example, we can see that we have correctly classified 9,000 patients,
which is a sum of 1,000 healthy and 8,000 sequence.
So, the accuracy is this number divided by the total number of patients, which is 10,000.
This gives us an accuracy of 90%.
Accuracy can easily be calculated as you can learn by using the accuracy score function.
Now, let's see how much is the accuracy of the spam detector model?
This is the answer to the question,
"Out of all the emails, how many did we classify correctly?"
Since we have correctly classified 800 out of the 1,000 emails,
then the answer is 80%.
Now, let's test your knowledge.
In this model, what is the accuracy?
Please write the numbers of percentage.
So, a number between 0 and 100.
This number can have decimals.