So let's go back to our two examples: a medical model and spam e-mail model.
Recall that for the medical model,
we have four possibilities: a true
positive which is when the patient is sick and we correctly diagnosed him as sick;
a true negative which is when the patient is not
sick and we correctly diagnose them as not sick;
a false positive which is when the patient is healthy
and we incorrectly diagnose them as sick;
and finally a false negative which is when the patient is
sick and we incorrectly diagnose them as healthy.
Now, let's forget about the two correct ones and focus only on the mistakes.
Below, we'll have a quiz.
Which one do you think is worse,
a false positive or a false negative?
In other words, what is the worst mistake,
to misdiagnose a healthy patient as sick or a sick patient as healthy?
Now, let's go back to our other model,
the spam e-mail model.
So we have two e-mails: one non-spam from our grandma telling us
she baked cookies and one spam from a questionable source.
Recall that for this model,
we again have four possibilities: a true positive
which is when the spam e-mail gets correctly sent into the spam folder;
a true negative which is when our grandma's e-mail
gets correctly sent to the inbox folder;
a false positive which grandma's e-mail accidentally gets sent to the spam folder;
and finally a false negative which is when
a spam e-mail accidentally gets sent to our inbox.
Now, again, let's forget about the two correct ones and focus only on the mistakes.
So below, there will be another quiz.
Which one do you think is worse,
a false positive or a false negative?
In other words, what is a worse mistake,
to accidentally send your grandma's email to
the spam folder or to accidentally send the spam email into your inbox?
Enter your answers below.